First off, I want to
thank you both for coming.
Yeah, yeah, what'd he do?
Uh, he didn't do anything.
Gosh, Tom,
I want to believe you.
Okay, the problem is,
the curriculum here
is not challenging enough
for Sheldon.
Now, he gets bored
and maybe doesn't
express himself
in the most productive way.
And so the square of sine
plus cosine equals one.
Sheldon.
I don't want to embarrass you,
so I'm going
to give you a moment
to think about
what you just said.
Ms. MacElroy.
What?
I'm wondering if you read
the book you assigned to us,
because I did.
WILKINS:
20 laps.
Cooper.
If you're going
to ask us to run,
don't you think you should
lead by example?
So you're saying he's being rude
to his teachers?
That's unacceptable.
I'll-I'll give him a talkin' to.
I don't know
if I'd call him rude.
Well, put a word on it.
Rude, let's go with rude.
Rude is good.
So what do you want us to do?
I want you to consider another
approach to his education.
- Okay.
- What does that mean?
I recently had a nice chat
with the head
of Wilmot Academy
for Gifted Children.
Now, I told her all about
Sheldon, and she seemed to think
he would be a perfect fit
over there.
MARY: We already looked
into private school.
We can't afford it.
- Not unless you're giving me a raise.
- I'm not.
Okay, just checking.
But I can tell you this.
Wilmot has been known
to give children like Sheldon
full scholarship.
Take a look at that.
- My goodness.
- No kidding.
Yeah, just read up on it.
Give it some thought.
MARY:
Hold on.
This place is in Dallas;
that's three hours away.
Well, yeah, but, uh,
what they do
in cases like yours,
they look for a local family
for him to live with.
And, George, Dallas?
Dallas is certainly close enough
that he can come home
on the weekends.
Look, we appreciate
you going to bat for him,
but he's just
a wee little thing.
We can't ship him off to Dallas.
Shouldn't we talk
about this first?
What's there to talk about,
George?
This could be a great
opportunity for Sheldon.
He's nine years old.
Oh, come on, you can't measure
him in Earth years.
You're saying he's an alien?
PETERSEN:
Well, in George's defense,
that idea has been
tossed around...
a little bit.
That's a bad joke.
Look, I understand
this is a big decision.
If you change your mind,
give me a call.
I'd be more than happy
to set up an interview.
- Uh, yeah. Thank you.
- You bet.
Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
- (door opens)
Maybe you all are the aliens.
(scoffs)
I love my job.
♪♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪♪
♪♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪♪
♪♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪♪
♪♪ I am a mighty little man ♪♪
♪♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪♪
Well, I don't understand how you
could turn this down.
This place looks fantastic.
It's 200 miles away, Mom.
I know where Dallas is.
I used to buy
my marijuana there.
Really?
I said "used to."
Then I got pregnant
with this one
and all the fun stopped.
All I am saying is that
this would be a great
opportunity for Sheldon.
I know, you're right.
Whoa, she's right?
I said the same thing
in Petersen's office,
you looked at me
like I was an idiot.
Yeah, that's the look.
Maybe y'all are being a
little selfish about this.
Selfish? We're thinking of him.
Well, that's all
well and good,
but maybe you should be
thinking about the whole world.
I mean,
what if Einstein's parents
had held him back?
We wouldn't even have the...
Well, I was gonna
say atomic bomb,
but there's probably
a better example.
Here's a crazy idea:
how about we ask Sheldon
what he thinks of all this?
Go ahead, but he's not gonna
want to go.
This is his home,
we're his family.
Sheldon, can you come in here
for a minute?!
Yes?
- Have a seat. We want to talk to you.
- All right.
So, today we found out
about a school in Dallas
for really smart kids.
When can I start?
Hold on. Dallas is far away,
so you'd have to live
with another family.
Do they have a dog?
Uh, we don't know.
Well, can you make some calls?
I guess, but wouldn't you miss
your mom and dad?
Oh.
Yes, I suppose I will.
So, when are you calling
about the dog?
You know him so well.
(sighs)
♪♪♪ ♪
What's wrong with them?
What are you
talking about?
They're so quiet.
Are they on medication?
No, they're just
smart like you.
I've been going to school
in a zoo.
Not sure about
these uniforms.
Kinda froufrou.
Sheldon, I've been looking over
your transcripts
and I must say,
I am very impressed.
Thank you.
What's your doctorate in?
Noncommutative Algebraic
Topology.
I like her.
It's gonna be weird around here
without Sheldon.
Don't you mean
less weird?
That's not nice.
I wasn't trying for nice.
You sure you're
not jealous
'cause your little brother's
moving up in the world?
Hey, I got plans of my own.
- Do tell.
- Soon as I graduate
high school, I'm gonna be
a professional male model.
That is hilarious.
What? I'm good-lookin'.
No, that you think you'll
graduate high school.
The model thing
was funny, too.
FLORA:
I must tell you,
in all the years I've been here,
I have never seen
such glowing letters
of recommendation
from a student's teachers.
- Well, that's real nice to hear.
- Now, listen to this:
"Putting aside his
superior intellect,
"Sheldon is a delight
to have in the class.
"He's fun-loving,
"easy to get along with,
and always ready to help
another student."
That doesn't sound like me
at all.
Sure it does, sweetie.
Dr. Douglas...
Oh, no. Please call me Flora.
Flora, I have to ask about
the living arrangements.
That's our main concern.
Well, I think I can
reassure you about that.
My husband and I have been
hosting a student
for the last several years
who recently graduated
and is now at Princeton.
So we have a guest room
available in our home.
That's very generous of you.
Does your husband work
at the school also?
No, he's retired.
He was an astrophysicist
for NASA.
Please tell me
you don't have a dog.
No. We're both allergic.
I'm tingling.
(chuckles)
- (knocking on door)
- SHELDON: Meemaw?
(knocking on door)
Meemaw.
W-Wow.
I know. I look great.
I got you a little
going away gift.
Come on in.
This necklace has been
in our family
for generations.
It belonged
to a Comanche warrior
who gave it to your
great-great-great-great grandma.
Why'd he give it to her?
Well, according
to family lore,
she was, uh, a very
accommodating young lady
and, uh, they hit it off.
That's a bird feather.
- Eagle feather.
- Doesn't matter.
I don't like birds;
birds are filthy.
Okay.
Fine.
One featherless
family heirloom
for you to take with you and
keep you safe while you're away.
You don't actually believe this
has magic powers, do you?
Oh, for God's sake,
just say "thank you."
Thank you.
(chuckles)
Mmm.
There's a price tag on it.
No, there's not.
Hello!
(crying)
Anybody home?
(crying):
Hi.
Mary.
He's gonna come home
every Friday night.
I didn't think I'd have
to deal with this
till he went to college.
You should thank
your lucky stars
he's not in college now.
(chuckles)
I'm still not sure that this
is the right thing to do.
Are you worried
that he won't like it
or are you worried
that he will?
You're not helping.
That's not my job.
I think of myself as
a speaker of truth.
If you're not gonna make
me feel better, go away.
(both laugh)
I'm sorry. You
are stuck with me.
(sighs, sniffles) - ADULT SHELDON:
As you can see,
even as a small child,
people cherished
having me around
and wept over my absence.
And no one took
my impending departure harder
than my best friend, Tam.
So you leave tomorrow?
Yes.
Dallas.
Cool.
It was touching
to watch Tam
bravely fight back tears.
(whirring)
Have you ever thought about
making the trains go clockwise?
No.
You should.
Brave, brave Tam.
(whistle blows)
You awake?
Yes.
Are you gonna miss me?
I haven't given it any thought.
Well, we're just lying here.
Think about it.
I am used to you.
I'm used to you, too.
It's not the same as liking you.
No.
To me, you're like string beans.
No one asks
for them,
no one wonders about them.
They're just there on the plate.
But you eat them, right?
Yes.
You're gonna miss me.
(sighs) All right,
let's say grace.
(sniffles) Guess I get
to hold hands with you now.
Guess so.
Maybe Sheldon's mittens
weren't such a bad idea.
Thank you, God, for
this food we are about
to receive
and for the nourishment
of our bodies.
And bless
the hands that
prepared it.
And, God, we ask that you watch
over our Sheldon...
as he begins
this wonderful new... (grunts)
(clears throat)
(exhales)
...as he begins
this wonderful new chapter
in his life.
- Amen.
- Amen. - Mm.
Why you cryin'?
Why you stupid?
So how'd it go in Dallas today?
GEORGE SR.:
Went fine.
Nice people.
Sheldon seemed very comfortable
with the whole thing.
Welcome! How was the drive?
Eh, a little traffic comin' into
the city but otherwise okay.
Sheldon, I want you to
meet my husband, Elliot.
Elliot, this
is Sheldon.
Well, it's nice to
meet you, young man.
I've heard a lot about you.
MARY: George, that is
not at all how they were.
- What are you talking about?
- There was
definitely something
off about those people.
Really?
What'd I miss?
Welcome!
How was the drive?
Eh, a little traffic comin' into
the city but otherwise okay.
- (creaking)
- Sheldon,
I want you to meet
my husband, Elliot.
Elliot, this
is Sheldon.
Nice to meet
you, young man.
I've heard a lot about you.
(cackling)
- (Flora cackling)
- GEORGE SR.: Oh, come on.
You're making it out like
they were some kind of monsters.
Sheldon has
his own room.
There's books
everywhere.
Even has a big old backyard
he won't play in.
Aren't you forgetting
somethin'?
What?
The underground laboratory.
GEORGE SR.:
I think it's called
a finished basement, honey.
I know what I saw.
Mary, it's been a long day.
Can we just have a quiet dinner?
Sure.
(quietly):
"Nice people."
Then why did we leave him there?
Because we love him and
we want the best for him.
This is tense.
Me and the kids
had a nice day.
Watched a lot of football.
You know, the Dolphins' helmet
has a dolphin on it.
And that dolphin
is also wearing a helmet.
But his helmet doesn't have
a dolphin on it...
it has the letter "M."
We talked about that
for an hour.
All right.
Dig in.
Excuse me.
Aren't we going to say grace?
Uh, we don't do that
in our house.
Oh.
But you're welcome to do so.
That's all right.
I don't believe in God.
Well, then why would you say
grace?
Because it makes my mom happy.
And why are you wearing
mittens?
Well, I don't know
where your hands have been.
Okay.
Maybe we should just eat.
(chuckles)
Do you like string beans?
No.
But I eat them.
(Flora chuckles)
♪♪♪♪
Sheldon, can you hear me?
It's your twin sister, Missy.
Everything's all right here,
but I think
Mom misses you real bad.
(sighs)
All right, I can't hear you,
so I'm gonna hang up now.
Good night.
MARY: I'm telling you,
this is a terrible idea.
- This is a terrible, terrible idea.
- MEEMAW: He's gonna be fine.
- You'll see.
- MARY: I can't believe you're okay with this.
MEEMAW:
I'm not okay with this.
I'm just trying
to be strong for you!
What? You thought him
leaving was a good idea.
Oh, I only said that because
you thought it was a bad idea.
You know how it's always
my nature to go the other way.
Say "up."
Up.
Down.
I'll see you in a bit.
Where are you off to?
I'm going to Dallas
to get Sheldon.
- Really?
- Yeah, really.
What about this being
a great opportunity for him?
Y'all want me to go or not?
- Yes! Go!
- Yes, and hurry up!
MEEMAW:
Get a move on, Tubby.
Where you going?
To get Sheldon.
Do I get a vote in this?
No.
Dang.
ADULT SHELDON: Sleep
didn't come easy that night,
knowing that, at any moment,
I could be decapitated.
And as if that
wasn't bad enough,
the bed in my room
had a dust ruffle,
which, to my young mind,
only meant
one thing: there was dust.
But, eventually,
I did drift off,
haunted by the memory,
the three of us
gathered around the piano
singing hippie folk music.
♪♪You will not see nothin'
like the mighty Quinn ♪♪
Come on. Sing along now.
♪♪Come all without ♪♪
Ha! ♪♪Come all within ♪♪
♪♪Come all within ♪♪
♪♪You will not see nothin' like
the mighty Quinn. ♪♪
(Elliot and Flora laughing)
"You'll not see nothin'."
Shame on whoever wrote that.
♪♪♪♪
Dad?
Yeah?
I'm glad you came to get me.
Me, too.
(radio clicks)
♪♪...nothing like
the mighty Quinn ♪♪
No!
- ♪♪Come all... ♪♪
- (click)
(birds chirping)
(grunts)
You got my message!
Hi-yah!
- SHELDON: No hugging! No hugging!
- (Missy laughing)
I mean, why'd I bother
becoming a teacher?
He knows what I'm gonna
say before I say it.
- Or I say it and look like a dumbbell.
- Mm-hmm.
Ms. Ingram,
can I offer a suggestion?
What?
- Never mind. You do it your way.
- No, no.
You tell me.
Tell me how I'm wrong.
You assumed an extra axiom
of Euclidean geometry
without stating it.
WILKINS:
Was he right?
Course he's right.
(chuckles)
He's always right.
(chuckling)
Tell you what I do.
I send him on little errands.
Like the other day, I told him,
"Go to the supply room
and get me a framastan."
(chuckles)
What's a framastan?
No such thing. I made it up.
(all laughing)
He was gone
the whole period!
That's genius.
I'm using that.
Don't use framastan.
That's mine.
(chuckling)
What's going on here?
You said he was going away.
Liar.
It's 11:00 in the
morning, guys.
(all laughing)