A simile directly compares
two things,
using the words "like" and "as."
"I slept
like a log."
"I'm hungry as a horse."
"Your love is like
bad medicine."
Exactly.
That's Bon Jovi.
Okay.
His hair is awesome.
Moving on.
Metaphors are different
from similes.
(sneezes)
ADULT SHELDON:
I've been called a germophobe,
but I do find
a single sneeze acceptable.
It could be caused
by dust, allergies...
really, whatever nasal irritant
floats your boat.
However...
during flu season...
...a second sneeze means
a plague is upon the land,
and it's every man for himself.
Where do you think
you're going?
Away from you.
Why's that?
I want to live.
I'm not sick.
Get back in your seat.
No, thank you.
You know the rules.
You can't leave
without a hall pass.
May I have a hall pass?
No, you may not.
Now get back in your seat.
ADULT SHELDON: Rules
are the pillars of society.
I love rules.
But what benefit are rules
to a dead man?
♪♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪♪
♪♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪♪
♪♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪♪
♪♪ I am a mighty little man ♪♪
♪♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪♪
Excuse me.
Do I look like
I'm getting sick to you?
You look a little pale.
Okay, good, that's normal.
Now, I understand Sheldon
is an exceptional child,
all right,
but when he
willfully disobeys
the order of a teacher,
there needs
to be some consequences here.
Oh, we couldn't
agree more.
What kind of punishment
are you thinking?
Well, Mary, in a case like this,
a few days of detention.
Really? That seems
a little harsh.
Oh, detention's
no big deal.
Now, my principal used to
whup my ass with a paddle.
That got
my attention.
Oh, yeah.
Those were the days.
Still have mine.
Ah.
Ol' Spanky.
(chuckles):
Whoa.
- Got a real nice grip on that thing.
- Yeah, George.
Had the equipment manager over
at the Astros make this for me.
The holes in it...
cut down on wind resistance.
Smart.
But these days you have
to have a consent form
to whack the kids.
I don't know
where this world's headed.
You ought to get one of those
for when Georgie acts up.
Like you never thought
about going upside his head
with a slab of wood.
You know, there was a time
this thing gave me tennis elbow.
(sneezes)
(continues
blowing nose)
Okay, Sheldon, come o...
Where'd he go?
Thataway.
♪♪♪ ♪
(sneezes)
(coughing)
(sneezing and coughing continue)
♪♪ Well, I'm running ♪♪
♪♪ Police on my back ♪♪
♪♪ I've been hiding ♪♪
- ♪♪ Police on my back ♪♪
- (grunting)
♪♪ There was a shooting ♪♪
♪♪ Police on my back ♪♪
♪♪ And the victim ♪♪
♪♪ Well, he won't come back ♪♪
What you
doing, kid?!
- ♪♪ Tuesday, Wednesday ♪♪
- (grunting)
♪♪ Thursday, Friday,
Saturday, Sunday ♪♪
(grunting)
ADULT SHELDON:
Enjoy this. It is, by far,
the most athletic two minutes
of my entire life.
♪♪ What have I done? ♪♪
(Meemaw laughing)
It's not funny.
Oh, come on, now.
Sheldon in detention...
that's funny.
I actually think
it'd be good for him.
He needs to learn
he's not special.
But he is special.
You know what I mean.
He can't just
walk out of a classroom
'cause he feels like it.
He was worried
about catching a cold.
That is a legitimate concern.
And now he's in danger
of being mugged
by a roomful of hoodlums.
He's not getting mugged.
It's half a dozen kids
doing homework
while a teacher watches 'em.
Although it might not hurt
to give Sheldon a few dollars
to buy himself
some protection.
That's actually not a bad idea.
(grunts, coughs)
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Is that
chewing tobacco?
It's chocolate Bazooka.
What do you want?
I have detention tomorrow,
and I thought you could
give me some tips.
That was pretty badass, you
walking out of class like that.
It was not my intention to be
bad "A" word, but thank you.
The only thing you need
to worry about in detention
is staying close
to the teacher.
If he leaves the room,
you go with him.
Why?
'Cause you're gonna
get your "A" word kicked.
Are you saying I'll be
in physical danger?
It's all the worst kids
in school
in one room for an hour.
What do you think's
gonna happen?
I thought we were gonna spend
the time regretting our actions
and thinking about how we could
be better in the future.
Well, you thought wrong.
Get lost.
You're both mean
and nice to me.
It's confusing.
(gags)
Maybe I'm doing this wrong.
(school bell rings)
Have you ever been in detention?
No.
But I do take
the school bus.
And that is no party.
It's like a mental hospital
on wheels.
That's a good use of simile.
Thanks.
Well, I'll see you tomorrow.
I hope.
(door closes)
- (school bell rings)
- (footsteps rapidly departing)
Hello. I'm here
for detention.
Where is the teacher?
Not here yet.
Oh.
I have three dollars.
Feel free to share it
with the others.
Would you prefer
a piece of paper?
I have some
in my briefcase.
It's here
if you change your mind.
All right, losers,
you know how this works.
One hour, no talking,
no horseplay.
Sheldon?
Hello, Mr. Givens.
Why are you here?
I didn't want to catch a cold
from Ms. MacElroy,
so I left her classroom
without a hall pass.
Well, something is going around.
I actually had a little tickle
in my throat.
Okay, time to go.
Nice meeting you.
Whoa, what-what are you doing?
You've heard of
fight or flight?
This is flight.
Not so funny
now, is it?
No. How long
is he suspended for?
A week.
And it goes on
his permanent record.
Well, that's
no big deal.
I had all kinds of stuff on my
permanent high school record.
Didn't stop me from being
a bartender for eight years.
I think the real issue we need
to deal with is his germ phobia.
Oh, yes,
you don't
want him turning
into Howard Hughes.
Growing his nails out.
Peeing in a jar.
Why would he pee into a jar?
I don't know why he peed in a jar,
I just know he did.
(sighs)
I hate to say it,
but I think
we need help with this.
- Like what?
- Maybe we could
take him to that nice doctor
who calmed him down
when he was convinced
he had an enlarged prostate?
Sheldon only calmed down
when the doctor told him
what happens in a prostate exam.
Poor thing.
Still talks about it.
Thank you for seeing us,
Doctor.
No problem.
So, what do you got today,
Sheldon?
Rickets?
Rabies?
Early-onset menopause?
Is he making a joke?
I believe so.
Humorous.
- Hmm.
- Sheldon's not sick,
but he has become overly
concerned with getting a cold
- or the flu.
- Well, any symptoms...
runny nose, achy,
- sore throat, fever?
- No.
All right, well, Sheldon,
if you do catch a cold,
or even the flu, it's...
it's not the end of the world.
The flu was the end of the world
for half a million Americans
during the influenza epidemic
of 1918.
- Really?
- In India
17 million people died.
Okay, I think we're getting
off the subject. Doctor,
Sheldon is afraid
to go to school
because he might get exposed
to some kind of bacteria
or virus.
So he's got a phobia?
It's not a phobia
if the threat is real.
You're a doctor,
you should know that.
Sheldon, you have
nothing to worry about.
Even if you did get the flu,
it's usually over in a week.
Why are we getting medical
advice from a man who smokes?
Sheldon.
O-Okay,
I have patients
who are actually sick.
Maybe we should wrap this up.
How come you don't
get sick all the time?
Well, I take precautions.
I wash my hands,
I wear gloves and a mask.
So, Mom, how was your day?
We're ignoring this?
Okay.
So pretty.
What's going on?
I'm not feeling so good.
(coughs loudly)
Biohazard! Biohazard!
Sucker.
WOMAN (on TV):
In national news,
an unusually early flu season
is buffeting the country.
Doctors say the strain,
originating in China,
is particularly severe.
Children and the elderly
are most at risk.
Sheldon, why are
you still up?
We're all gonna die!
...about the local cattle...
This isn't funny!
I know, baby, I know.
But you need to
understand that sometimes
the news says those things
just to scare people.
Well, it's working!
Come here.
I know you don't
believe in this,
but I'm gonna
do it anyway.
(sighs)
Lord, I pray for
my son Sheldon
that you protect him from
all illness and disease,
and keep him healthy
and keep him safe,
and protect him from
his head to his toes,
inside and out. Amen.
You're right.
I don't believe in that.
But it did feel good. Thanks.
In the Bible, that's called
a hedge of protection.
Why do you keep smiling?
You need to look
at your mask, baby.
SHELDON:
Missy?!
We have to go to school,
and Sheldon doesn't?
- That's not fair.
- Sure it is.
Sheldon loves school
and can't go.
You hate school
and have to. Fair.
GEORGE SR.:
He still has
to spend his day doing chores.
Can't sit around
playing with his trains.
Yeah, put him to work.
Good parenting, Dad.
Oh, I'm glad you approve.
I do.
Where you going?
I'm gonna give Sheldon
a list of chores.
You're actually
taking my advice?
Yes.
Well, how about that?
Hey, you were due.
(door closes)
Proud of you, George.
Sheldon?
Yes.
The door's locked.
Can you open it?
No.
What on earth?
- Hello.
- What are you doing?
I made a real germ-proof
hedge of protection.
Oh, honey,
you can't stay in there.
I've got a refrigerator,
I've got my sleeping bag,
and anything else I need
I can make out of Legos.
What's with
the Halloween costume?
In case of a breach.
Stay right there.
That's my plan.
George?
Just when you think
he's gonna zig,
you get
a big old zag.
It's ridiculous. I'm...
I'm gonna take it down.
No, you can't force him out
of a phobia.
What do we do?
He can't live
in there.
Well, actually, he can.
He's got the refrigerator
and a sleeping bag.
And he can always
go potty in the sink.
I think I'll take
the kids to school.
I'm sure he'll be out
by the time you get home.
Not sure why you
think that, but okay.
- Mom?
- Yes, Shelly.
Can you close the door?
I need to use the sink.
(Meemaw laughs)
- Tammy Cook?
- Here.
- Georgie Cooper?
Sheldon Cooper? Absent.
- Where's your brother?
- Home.
Is he okay?
Yeah, he's just...
(bell dings)
Actually, it's not
looking good for him.
He might not make it.
- Oh, that's terrible.
- I know.
I love him so much.
If anything ever happened,
I don't know what I'd do.
Aw.
MARY:
Shelly, if you don't mind
- me asking, what's your long-term plan here?
- I'm working
on the math to turn the garage
into a self-sustaining
ecosystem.
- Okay. And what exactly does that mean?
- Well, all I need
is sunlight and a few seeds
to grow unlimited food
which I'll fertilize
with my own feces.
(laughing):
This just gets better.
If you're not gonna
help, please go inside.
This is not a show.
Now that's where I disagree.
- (sighs)
- (giggles)
Shelly, baby,
please come on out.
I can't.
Come on.
I'm your mommy.
Do it for your mommy.
No.
(sighs)
But I'm your mommy.
(laughing):
Y'all are killing me.
(laughing)
(sighs) - (laughing):
"I'm your mommy."
I think the saddest part
about it is just how sad it is.
Is there anything
that we can do?
I don't know.
A hug might help.
Of course.
What's wrong
with you two?
Don't you care
about my brother?
(fake crying)
Aw.
(crying):
Oh, Sheldon.
That's it. I've had
enough of this nonsense.
If you don't come out,
I'm coming in!
One, two,
- three.
- Breach! Breach!
- You come here right this instant!
- No.
Oh!
♪♪ That's great, it starts
with an earthquake ♪♪
- Sheldon!
- ♪♪ Birds and snakes and aeroplanes... ♪♪
You can't run away
from me forever.
I don't have to do it forever.
Just till you get tired.
MEEMAW:
Mary,
I'm gonna run
and go get my video camera.
Don't catch him till I get back.
This is not a joke!
Sheldon, get over here!
- ♪♪ It's the end of the world ♪♪
- (Meemaw laughs)
- ♪♪ As we know it ♪♪
- Get over here.
Sheldon Lee Cooper, get here.
Right now.
Oh, Lord, I think
I'm gonna wet myself.
Get! You come here!
Sheldon Lee Cooper!
♪♪ I feel fine. ♪♪
Look at that.
St. Mary drinking alcohol.
God saw what just happened.
He gets it.
Mind if I take a crack
at catching the Road Runner?
What are you gonna do
that I couldn't do?
Oh, a little trick I learned
trying to get prairie dogs
out of the hole.
Of course we'd whack off
their heads with a golf club.
I'm not gonna do that
to Sheldon.
(sighs)
(singsongy):
Oh, Moon Pie,
I've got a little treat for you.
Chocolate chip?
Mm-hmm, right out of the oven.
Good. That means
they're sterile.
(laughs)
Why don't you come on out here
and... have a couple?
I can't do that.
Okay, I tell you what.
I'm gonna just put 'em
right out here,
and you can come out
and get one when you're ready.
How about that?
I'm gonna put 'em down
right... here.
Aah! (laughs)
Come on! Oh. (laughs)
Listen to me, buster.
- Okay.
- You are
a lot of things, Sheldon.
You are cute, smart, hygienic.
But most of all...
you... are a Texan.
So?
So Texans
aren't afraid of nothin'!
Rattlesnakes, Indians,
the Mexican Army.
Do you imagine that Sam Houston
was scared of a little old cold?
No.
Jim Bowie?
Sissy Spacek?
I... guess not?
You're damn right,
because they're Texans
through and through.
Now I want you to quit hiding
in this plastic bubble,
and I want you to
come out here and
eat your cookies
out in the world like a man!
Like a Texan man!
(Meemaw sighs)
I'm impressed.
Me, too.
I thought I'd lost him
at Sissy Spacek.
Whew! (chuckles)
ADULT SHELDON:
As you can see,
my meemaw successfully
lured me back into the world
by reminding me
of my brave Texas ancestors.
Their blood ran
through my veins.
I was a true son
of the Lone Star State.
Albeit a true son
with an incredibly fragile
immune system.
I woke up the next morning
with a temperature of 102
and a head packed full
of mucus.
However, there was
a silver lining.
♪♪ Soft kitty, warm kitty ♪♪
♪♪ Little ball of fur ♪♪
♪♪ Happy kitty, sleepy kitty ♪♪
♪♪ Purr, purr, purr. ♪♪
Sing it again, Mom.
First, blow your nose.
(blows nose)
♪♪ Soft kitty, warm kitty ♪♪
♪♪ Little ball of fur ♪♪
♪♪ Happy kitty, sleepy kitty ♪♪
♪♪ Purr, purr, purr. ♪♪