ADULT SHELDON:
The average American consumes
55 pounds of beef per year.
And then there's Texas,
where we can knock that off
in a couple of months.
Maybe faster, if we're talking
about smoked brisket...
♪ ♪♪ ♪
...curiously,
the one cut of beef
that Texans and Jews
agree upon.
(mouth full): This is
really good, Meemaw.
Really good?
You're spitting the best
brisket in Texas
all over the damn table.
Close your mouth
when you eat.
Or aim your face
the other way.
Connie, one of these days,
you got to give me the recipe.
You bet. For sure.
- One of these days.
- Oh, come on.
You can't hold on to it forever.
Mean that much to you?
Mary and I were dating
about a month
when she brought me
home for dinner.
I took one bite of this brisket,
and I knew I loved
your daughter.
Gee, thanks.
Kind of like Sleeping Beauty,
except Dad kissed meat.
(chuckles)
I tell you what.
You go get a...
piece of paper and a pencil,
I'll write it down for you.
Okay. It's happening...
That's the fastest
I've seen him run.
It's the only time
There you go.
Okay.
I might make it
this weekend.
Or you could try
a vegetable.
Vegetable?
That's funny.
Okay.
Now, this is for
your eyes only.
You're not to share it
with anybody.
I never... I would never.
You're a horrible person.
- (chuckles)
- What'd it say?
I want to know
what it said.
- Me, too.
- Just eat.
Can I read it?
You are a horrible person.
Ain't I? (laughs)
All right, that's enough
about the brisket.
You kids excited for
the church picnic tomorrow?
- Not really.
- I don't know.
Oh, come on.
You all saw the flier.
The three "F" s:
food, fun, and fellowship.
MEEMAW:
And I'm bringing
a big slab of my brisket.
That's it.
15 years in this family, and
all the time I've been nothing
but a good,
supportive son-in-law.
I always treated
your daughter right,
I gave you three
beautiful grandchildren.
Only thing I ever asked in
return was that damn recipe.
You're right.
Get another piece of paper.
I'll write it down.
Don't mess with me, Connie.
Get the paper before
I change my mind.
You're gonna do it
to him again, aren't you?
I kind of have to.
♪♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪♪
♪♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪♪
♪♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪♪
♪♪ I am a mighty little man ♪♪
♪♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪♪
(cow mooing)
(toilet flushes) - MARY: George,
she was just fooling with you.
GEORGE:
No, no, she's mean.
She got a black heart.
MARY:
She does not.
GEORGE: Why do you
always side with her?
MARY:
Well, she is my mother.
GEORGE:
And there it is.
There's the problem.
You should be siding
with me.
- MARY: Over brisket?
- GEORGE: It's notjust brisket.
It's the way she's been
treating me since day one.
Like I'm some kind of
loser, a booby prize.
- "Booby prize."
- MARY: What was that?
Georgie, you mind
your own business.
What did I do?
What's going on?
Mom and Dad are fighting.
What about?
Brisket.
If they get a divorce,
who do you think
you'll pick to live with?
Well, Mom, of course.
I want Mom. Pick again.
(sighs)
♪ ♪♪ ♪
I thought Dad was coming.
No, he had work to do.
- What kind of work?
- I don't know. Coaching stuff.
Can't he do it
after the picnic?
- No, Missy, he cannot.
- Why not?
Enough.
How come Georgie's
not going?
He's grounded for eavesdropping
on me and your father.
Well, I hope he learned
his lesson.
Is this about the recipe?
I bet he's mad 'cause you
always side with Meemaw.
And how would you know that?
Georgie told me.
Are you and Dad
getting a divorce?
'Course not.
Well, if you do,
I want to live with you.
Sheldon, no one's
getting a divorce.
But thank you, honey.
You know this
all goes away
if you just give him your
recipe for the brisket.
I know.
And?
I guess it's not going away.
(football announcer speaking
over TV)
I wasn't
eavesdropping.
Don't worry about it.
I just don't see why
I got grounded.
What are you complaining about?
You didn't want to go
to church picnic anyway.
I like complaining.
I'm good at it.
I'll be right back.
Mind if I have
a sip of your beer?
You mind if I dip your head
in the compost heap?
You could have
just said no.
♪ ♪♪ ♪
- What are you doing?
- (gasps)
Nothing!
Get out of here.
You're looking for
her brisket recipe.
All of a sudden you got smart?
I said get out of here.
I won't tell, I swear.
All right, help me look.
- Ooh.
- Found it?
No, this is her French toast.
You're not looking
for French toast.
She does make it good, though.
Did you know
she puts vanilla extract
in her whipped cream?
I did not.
Quarter teaspoon.
- Georgie?
- Yeah?
We're looking for brisket!
Cranky.
- (door opens)
- MARY: We're home.
Be cool.
I'm cool. You be cool.
(leather squeaking)
(chair clatters)
Real cool.
He thought I wrote it down.
What a dope.
MAN: Seltzer...
(continues speaking over TV)
...hair tonic. Hair tonic.
(man continues speaking over TV)
Need help putting the kids down?
No, thank you, I've been
taking care of them all day.
I think I can
finish the job.
Oh, come on, don't do that.
Don't do what?
Never mind.
Just so you know,
Sheldon and Missy won
the three-legged race
because she told him
a bee was chasing them,
and you missed it.
I'm sorry, I-I just needed
a break from your mother.
Yeah, well, you took a break
from your family.
How long is this feud
between you two gonna go on?
That's up to her.
You are both such...
stubborn...
donkey butts!
- (Missy laughing)
- Missy!
Go to bed.
MISSY:
You don't know it's me.
(running footsteps, door closes)
(crickets chirping)
Hey.
What do you want?
Don't be that way.
I brought you a cold one.
Thanks.
I still don't like you.
(chuckling)
Would this change
your feelings?
Is that it?
The Holy Grail.
What changed your mind?
You not going
to the picnic today,
that hurt Mary
and the twins.
I cannot have that
on my heart.
- Is that so?
- Absolutely.
Look me in the eye
and tell me
this is the actual recipe.
George, what you have
in your hand
is the exact
step-by-step instructions
on how to make my brisket.
I have never written it down
until tonight because...
I was afraid
someone might steal it.
But I'm entrusting
this to you,
and I hope that someday,
when the time is right,
you will see fit to share it
with one of your children.
Connie, I don't
know what to say.
Don't call me Connie.
- Call me Mom.
- (chuckles)
Thanks, Mom.
You're welcome, son.
Mmm.
♪ ♪♪ ♪
(quietly):
What a dope.
♪♪ What I want, you've got ♪♪
♪♪ And it might be
hard to handle ♪♪
♪♪ But like the flame
that burns the candle... ♪♪
ADULT SHELDON: The next morning,
my dad embarked
on a doomed quest
to make the perfect brisket.
Can I help you?
Matter of fact, you can.
♪♪ You pull them
all together... ♪♪
I need 12 pounds of prime Angus
with a medium deckle,
ideally slaughtered in the
spring, no later than mid-June.
♪♪ You make my dreams
come true... ♪♪
ADULT SHELDON:
For the spice rub,
Meemaw had him drive
to New Orleans
to buy ground coffee
from Café Du Monde,
and seven ounces of something
called "holy ghost root"
from a voodoo woman
named Madam Laveau.
♪♪ Yeah... ♪♪
Could you grind my root for me?
I-I'm-a... I'm-a rub it
on brisket.
ADULT SHELDON: Then back home,
he applied the spice rub
with such erotic tenderness,
it made my mother
a little jealous.
♪♪ Well, you... ♪♪
Finally, the cooking began.
♪♪ You make my dreams
come true... ♪♪
♪♪ Oh, yeah,
I've been waiting for... ♪♪
14 hours of cooking.
And basting.
♪♪ You make my dreams
come true... ♪♪
And spritzing.
♪♪ Me, you, me, you, me... ♪♪
And tending to the fire.
♪♪ Oh, my, you make my dreams
come true... ♪♪
Until it was finally time
to let the meat rest.
♪♪ Waiting for, waiting for,
waiting for ♪♪
♪♪ Waiting for,
waiting for, waiting for ♪♪
♪♪ You make my dreams... ♪♪
Oh...
Rest, my darling.
Rest.
Mmm. This Café Du Monde coffee
is very good.
They make it with chicory.
And what does it do
to the brisket?
Oh, I have no idea.
Then...
why did you send George
all the way to New Orleans?
Well, they don't sell this
around here.
Mmm.
Here we go.
15 years and 14 hours later.
Best brisket in Texas.
GEORGE SR.:
Connie, you evil bitch!
It's smoother
than regular coffee.
That wasn't the recipe.
You looked me in the eye,
and you lied to me.
Oh, Mom.
You broke into my home
and tried to steal it.
Oh, George.
You told her we
went over there?
(gasps)
Oh, George Jr.
I didn't say nothing.
I was cool.
I am loving this.
I don't want this woman
in my house anymore.
- She is my mother.
- She is the devil.
And what if the kids
want to see her?
Fine.
Schedule it
for when I'm not here.
Or when I'm dead.
And quit drinking my coffee.
Turn off your train,
we've got to talk.
- (train stops)
- About what?
Mom is so upset
about Dad and Meemaw,
she might want a divorce.
No one's getting divorced.
How do you know?
(whistles)
Great, now I have
to throw that out.
Mother-in-laws are always held
in low regard by the father.
It rarely leads
to a breakup of the family.
MISSY:
He's right.
Fred and Wilma
are still happily married.
I think if we can figure out
a way for Dad to get
Meemaw's brisket recipe,
this all goes away.
I don't see how
we can accomplish that.
(train clatters)
Put that down.
That's not a toy.
Sure it is.
Choo choo.
MEEMAW:
Choo choo...
Choo choo.
Open wide, Moonpie.
Here comes the choo choo train.
Choo choo.
Mmm. Isn't that good?
(chuckles)
That's Meemaw's famous brisket.
Would you like
the secret recipe?
(gasps)
You promise not to tell anybody?
Of course you're not gonna
tell anybody.
I start with a tablespoon
of cumin,
and then a cup
of brown sugar, and...
I know the recipe.
What?
She told it to me.
When?
February 14, 1982.
I was 23 months old,
it was Valentine's Day,
and Mom and Dad
went out for dinner.
You were there.
Don't you remember?
(sighs)
(wind whistling softly)
I got nothing.
You can really remember
when you were that little?
Uh-huh. You were there, too.
You were still struggling
with potty training.
(chuckling):
I don't think so.
Oh, yes. Meemaw used to call you
Mr. Soggy Pants.
Nuh-uh.
(laughs):
Mr. Soggy Pants.
Quit it. This is serious.
Sheldon, you've got
to tell Dad that recipe.
But Meemaw told me
it was a secret.
If you don't, and Mom and Dad
get a divorce, it's your fault.
All right.
Fine.
Good job, Soggy Pants.
(referee whistle blowing
over TV)
Dad, could you please
come into the living room?
What for?
My brain
did something impressive
and I'd like to share it
with you.
Hmm.
(George Sr. grunts)
What are you doing here?
Same as you.
I want to see
what his brain did.
Please have a seat.
All right.
(grunts)
GEORGE SR.:
Well?
I know Meemaw's brisket recipe.
What?
No, you don't.
Yes, I do.
And in order to bring peace
to this family,
I'm prepared to make it public.
You're bluffing.
One tablespoon of cumin,
one cup of brown sugar,
two tablespoons
of smoked paprika...
Okay, okay, stop.
No, no, no. Keep going.
How do you know
the recipe, Shelly?
Meemaw told it to me
on Valentine's Day, 1982.
You were out with Dad
seeing Cannonball Run
at the dollar theater.
That's impossible, you weren't
even two years old.
Three tablespoons
of dried mustard,
one cup of Lone Star beer...
Okay.
Go ahead.
Give it to your father.
I can write it down for you.
That's okay,
I don't want it.
(quietly):
You have got to be kidding me.
Connie, you've had
every opportunity
to give me that recipe
and you never did,
because you've always
treated me like an outsider.
No, she has not.
Oh, of course I have.
See? She admits it.
- (sighs)
- Damn right, I do.
Never thought you were good
enough for my daughter.
There you were, riding around
on that dumb motorcycle,
knocking her up.
Why don't you kids
go in the kitchen
and fix yourselves
some ice cream?
I'm not going anywhere.
Hey. I get it.
I have a daughter.
I wouldn't want her bringing
home someone like that.
But I've come
a hell of a long way since then.
Okay, you're right.
George.
I'm sorry.
That means more to me
than any recipe.
Come here.
(Meemaw chuckles)
ADULT SHELDON:
Don't let the hug fool you.
The minute she went home,
he made me give him the recipe.
Here we go, maiden voyage.
Mmm, mmm.
Hot damn.
GEORGE SR.:
(George Sr. moaning)
Hot damn!
MARY (laughs):
George! Language.
Sheldon.
Want some?
Uh, no, thank you.
I'm not hungry.