- (View-Master clicks)
- ADULT SHELDON: In any ecosystem,
you'll find a delicate balance
between predator and prey.
Some well-known predators
include Panthera leo,
Ursus arctos,
and star of the
1987 film Predator,
Predator.
Now, examples of prey
include Oryctolagus cuniculus,
Gallus gallus domesticus,
and weighing in at 58 pounds
soaking wet,
Diminutive homo novus...
curiously, a close relative
of Gallus gallus domesticus.
♪ Two, three, four ♪
("Fix Me" by Black Flag plays)
(kids shouting)
♪ Fix me, fix my head ♪
♪ Fix me please,
I don't want to be dead... ♪
LUIS:
Cooper.
Your stop.
Would you mind dropping me off
closer to my house?
You know I'm not allowed
to do that.
What if I did your taxes?
Sorry, kiddo.
I could've gotten you
a nice refund.
ADULT SHELDON:
The perilous journey
from the bus stop
to my front door
was 97.5 meters.
FYI, insisting on using
the metric system
in East Texas is another reason
I was hunted by predators.
♪♪
(panting)
Homo novus needs a Yoo-hoo.
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
Jiu-jitsu?
I've decided
to learn self-defense.
- Why?
- I'm quite small,
and will be for several years,
maybe even more
if I'm a late bloomer.
Your dad's big,
maybe you'll take after him.
We both like my mom.
I think that's where
the similarities end.
You know, one of
the books mentioned
a Vietnamese martial art.
Vovinam. I'm a blue belt.
- Wow.
- Don't be impressed.
It's what you get when
your mom buys the uniform.
Do you remember any of it?
I don't even know
where the belt is.
The book says jiu-jitsu
is based on using
your attacker's
momentum against them.
It's just physics. Come at me.
Like, run at you?
Well, I'm new to this,
so maybe just walk quickly.
And what happens
when I get to you?
I'll use your inertia
to take you down.
Okay.
♪ Hit it ♪
♪ It takes two
to make a thing go right ♪
(grunting)
And when does inertia
take me down?
(straining): Any second.
♪ I got an idea
that I wanna share ♪
♪ You don't like it,
so what? I don't care... ♪
I don't understand.
I'm using physics.
(grunting)
♪ All of my followers 'cause
all I want is respect... ♪
This leg lock is called
an Outside Ashi Garami.
What happens next?
That depends,
is this your foot or mine?
♪ It takes two
to make it outta sight. ♪
♪♪
LUIS:
Cooper. Your stop.
(panting)
Ahh.
I bowled a new high
score last night.
Nice.
- I got two turkeys.
- What's a turkey?
It's three strikes
in a row.
Why do they call it a turkey?
Well, when they first
invented bowling,
they used to just throw
frozen turkeys at the pins.
Eventually,
they switched to balls
to cut down on the smell.
Why you lying to her?
I find it keeps
my mind sharp. (chuckles)
Sheldon, breakfast!
SHELDON:
Be right there!
MARY:
Sheldon!
Coming!
(rustling)
Hello.
MARY: Shelly,
you all right?
Yes.
I must be a little sore
from doing jiu-jitsu
with Tam yesterday.
Why were you doing jiu-jitsu?
We're boys.
Roughhousing is what we do.
(popping)
- What was that?
- What was what?
That sound.
- What sound?
- (popping)
What's all this?
An extra layer
of protection.
Protection from what?
Sweetie, is someone
bothering you?
- Yes.
- Who is it?
I'd rather not talk about it.
No, I want a name
right now.
Mary.
Have you been hurting him?
Only with my words.
Tell me who
it is, Shelly.
Mary, slow down.
Don't tell me
to slow down.
- Someone is bullying him.
- Okay.
Okay.
Sheldon, you can't go to school
wearing all that.
Go to your room and take it off.
Yes, sir.
(rustling, popping)
You go with him.
But my cereal's gonna get soggy.
- Go.
- (sighs)
I'd like one nice morning.
Why aren't you
more upset about this?
I am. I just think we should
proceed with caution.
- Someone is hurting our son.
- I understand.
But handling bullies
is tricky. It...
It's easy to
make things worse.
And what makes you the expert?
Honey, I was a bully.
MEEMAW:
He's right.
You get involved in this
in the wrong way,
and they'll take it out
on Sheldon.
Well, I'm sorry,
but I can't just stand by.
Georgie, I need to talk
to you, and wake up,
you're gonna be late.
Got it covered.
I slept in my clothes.
Oh, Lord. Look, somebody has
been picking on your brother.
You know anything
about it?
No.
You better not be
covering for anybody.
I'm not. Most kids
at school ignore him,
and the girls
all think he's cute.
It's kind of annoying.
Well, I need you
to look after him.
Why?
Because I'm your mother,
and I'm asking you nicely.
What if I don't want to?
I don't care, you're doing it.
How was that nice?
So there I was flying
above the city,
but when I woke up,
I couldn't fly.
That's like the dream you had
where you were dating Madonna,
but when you woke up,
you weren't.
Exactly.
You ever have the ones where
your teeth are falling out?
Better my teeth
than my hair, but...
- Sheldon?
- Over here.
- What are you doing?
- Hiding.
From who?
Is Billy the one
giving you trouble?
No.
His dad?
No...
She's a demon.
The little Sparks girl?
You're kidding.
She seems so sweet.
He says she slaps him around,
takes his lunch money.
She even put a tadpole
down his shirt.
Poor kid,
he tucks in those shirts.
- She looks harmless.
- She's cute.
So she probably gets
away with stuff.
I'm like that.
I wonder if stray cats
poop in that sandbox.
MARY:
George.
You need to talk
to her parents.
Me? Why me?
Because you're more
intimidating than me.
That's rich.
Hey, Billy.
Hello, Missy's dad.
- Is your father home?
- Yes.
Could you get him for me?
Happy to.
Dad, it's Missy's dad!
He's also Sheldon's dad!
HERSCHEL:
Well, howdy, neighbor.
Hey, Herschel.
What brings you by?
Chickens too loud?
- Nah, they been fine.
- Good, good.
Fried up the noisy one
last week.
That shut him up.
Anyway, how can I help?
Uh, well...
It's come to my
attention that, uh...
Sheldon's run into a bit
of trouble with your daughter.
What kind of trouble?
He says she been beating on him.
- My Bobbi?
- Yeah.
This one? The six-year-old?
Bobbi, get over here!
You realize I've taken dumps
bigger than this kid.
- Hi, Daddy.
- Hey, babydoll, uh,
Mr. Cooper says that you've
been picking on Sheldon.
- Now, is that true?
- No, Daddy.
Are you sure?
Okay, go wash up
for dinner.
I don't know what
to tell you, George.
I mean, is it,
is it possible
your son has a
little crush on her?
Oh, I don't think
he's wired that way.
Oh, are you saying
that he's a...
No, no, I'm saying he's
a bookworm. (chuckles)
Unless she's math or a
dictionary, he ain't interested.
- Mm.
- Yeah.
Thanks for hearin' me out.
Your wife sent you over here,
didn't she?
- I don't want to talk about it.
- (chuckles)
I bet she did!
Not talkin' about it!
Tell her I said hi!
(chuckles)
How'd it go?
Uh, good. Yeah.
I handled it.
Oh, thank the Lord.
Yeah. Me and the Lord.
Team effort.
(whirring)
Hello, Bobbi.
You told on me.
Well, actually,
my brother
figured it out, so, technically,
I would argue that I didn't.
Doesn't matter.
Uh, I should let you know,
I've read a book
on jiu-jitsu.
And I'm prepared
to throw it at you.
(screaming)
Shelly, it's just Bactine.
Aah!
I didn't even put it
on you yet.
(shushing softly)
You want to tell me
what happened?
Bobbi Sparks
came into the garage...
And she attacked you?
Not exactly.
I tried to use jiu-jitsu on her,
but I tripped and fell.
Aw, baby. I'm so sorry
you're havin' to deal with this.
It's okay.
German philosopher
Friedrich Nietzsche said,
"That which does not kill us
makes us stronger."
And do you feel stronger?
No.
How are the knees?
Better, thank you.
Good.
And regarding this jiu-jitsu
stuff, you should know
that a man's not supposed
to raise his hand to a woman.
Oh, I won't. I don't want
to hurt myself again.
Did you ever have a bully
when you were growing up?
Have you met your grandma?
I thought you said
you handled it next door.
I did say that.
Where you goin'?
To handle it.
(quietly): Should've been you
in the first place.
What?
Good luck!
(door shuts)
Way to go, Scooby!
That's my newshound!
Missy, I could
really use your help.
With what?
I'm being bullied
by Bobbi Sparks.
Hilarious. Go on.
Madame Doo!
That's me!
Mom says a man should never
raise his hand to a woman.
But I believe I've
found a loophole.
You're a woman, so
you're allowed to hit her
as much as you want.
Why would I do that?
Because I'm willing to pay you.
How much?
My life savings,
four dollars.
That's a good start.
Now, let's talk TV privileges.
What do you want?
Complete control
every afternoon for two months.
That's when
Professor Proton is on.
I know. Sucks for you.
(sighs)
I'm on fire!
(laughs)
Hello, Brenda.
Oh, hey, Mary.
How many lanes you need?
Actually, I'm here
to talk to you.
Seems that our kids
are havin' a little problem.
Yeah. Herschel told me.
Oh, good, good.
So, I was wondering what
you're plannin' to do about it,
'cause the situation doesn't
seem to be gettin' any better.
Well, if you haven't noticed,
I'm at work right now.
I see that.
But you understand
that your daughter's being
abusive to my son.
Well, maybe your son needs
to grow a pair.
And in due time, he will.
But right now, I expect you
to teach your children
how to behave.
Connie Tucker
to the front desk, please.
Connie Tucker.
Why are
you calling her?
You say my daughter's
harassing your son.
Well, her daughter's
harassing me.
Hey, Mary.
- What are you doin' here?
- Well,
I was hopin' to have a rational
conversation about Shelly,
but there's only one person
being rational.
(grunts)
Uh, and it ain't you.
Could you excuse us
for just a minute?
Do you understand
that you are in the place
where I socialize three
to four days a week?
So you care more about bowling
than your grandson?
Of course not.
I'm just saying
maybe there's a better way
to go about it.
Now, I'm warnin' you,
Brenda is one mean...
I know you don't like
bad language,
but we are in a bowling alley...
one mean bitch.
Well, I can be mean, too.
Okay, you listen to me.
You get your kid
in line or I...
What are you doing?
Get out of here.
This is my place of business.
And now I see
where your daughter gets it.
BRENDA:
You know what?
I have been nothin' but nice
to you and your family
since the day y'all moved in,
and I'm over it.
Watching you walk
around all holier
than thou, like you're better
than everyone else.
Well, guess what,
you're not.
I'm gonna pray for you.
She says that to me
all the time.
I'm not even sure she does it.
How'd it go?
I don't want
to talk about it.
(sniffs)
Is that pine?
We're not talkin' about it.
- (doorbell rings)
- And you get that!
- Herschel.
- Hey, George.
It has come to my attention
that your wife went to speak
with my wife
at her place of work,
- and, uh...
- She send you over here?
Uh, the-the important thing is
that I'm here to tell you
that, uh, Mary's behavior
was inappropriate.
You know, it's interesting.
When I came to your house,
you were laughin',
and...
now you're all serious.
Why is that?
What do you say
we go talk about this
somewhere
a little more comfortable?
MARY (sharply):
Who's at the door?
(chickens clucking)
Make yourself at home.
Oh, boy.
You hang out in here?
Sure.
Once you get used to the smell,
it's not so bad.
(chuckles)
I coach a high
school football team.
This smells like petunias.
(laughs)
I like to...
take a break
from the family and...
come out here
and watch the games.
- Ooh!
- (chuckles)
(music playing)
Your wife don't mind?
She don't know.
She's scared
to death of chickens.
- Is that right?
- Once I found out,
buildin' this coop
was a no-brainer.
(laughing)
♪ I sure did love... ♪
You were gone so long.
How did it go?
Well...
(English accent):
One lump or two?
Two, please.
Billy?
Why would I want
lumpy tea?
Isn't he pretty?
Very pretty.
I feel pretty.
♪ Girl, you know it's true ♪
♪ My love... ♪
I handled it.
Thank you so much.
We're family. It's what we do.
(Herschel
and George Sr. chuckling)
Listen, I'm sorry my wife
went down to the bowling alley.
Please, I'm sorry Brenda
made me come to your door.
I'm not.
This is the most fun
I've had all week.
I-I feel bad about
the whole thing with the kids.
Hey, it happens.
I know, but Bobbi shouldn't be
beatin' on Sheldon like that.
- It's not okay.
- What's not okay
is Sheldon gettin' beat
up by a little girl.
Well...
Yeah.
(both chuckling)
Look, I'll talk to Bobbi.
I don't know if it'll help,
but I'll try.
- Hey, you're a good man.
- Mm.
Yeah, I-I should
be headin' back.
Mm.
All right, well, look,
come on by anytime.
Yeah.
You know, we should probably get
our stories straight
before we talk
to our respective...
- mates.
- Sure.
What do you want to say?
How 'bout this?
We had words,
it almost got ugly,
but we came to an understanding.
- I like that.
- Yeah.
You want to take
a swing at me?
Make it look real?
I have a freakishly high
tolerance for pain.
No, no.
But you're sweet for offering.
- You have a good night.
- You, too, pal. (chuckles)
BRENDA:
Herschel!
Where the hell
are you?!
Shh.
(quietly):
I built a hidey-hole under here,
but there's only room
for one of us.
Where is that fat dumbass?
Believe it or not, that means
I'm gettin' lucky tonight.
Y'all have an
odd relationship.
Love is a mysterious thing.
BRENDA:
Herschel!
ADULT SHELDON: Existing in a
world of predators isn't easy,
but we prey have developed
several natural defenses
to help us survive.
There's playing dead,
- warning calls, camouflage...
- (bicycle bell rings)
♪♪
...and, last
but certainly not least,
good old-fashioned
running away.
(screaming)
A little screaming
never hurts either.